<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Nerd DAO Hub Blog</title>
        <link>https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/nerddao/blog</link>
        <description>Nerd DAO Hub Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 20:03:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NerdBogota]]></title>
            <link>https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/nerddao/blog/Nerd-Bogota</link>
            <guid>Nerd-Bogota</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 20:03:23 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[From all over the world Nerds have travelled to Bogota, Colombia to participate in the EthBogota hackathon and DevCon. The hackathon has come to an end with over 900 hackers participating and over 200 projects made over a single weekend. It is the biggest hackathon ever in LatAm.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/KBg0WjR.jpg" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>From all over the world Nerds have travelled to Bogota, Colombia to participate in the EthBogota hackathon and DevCon. The hackathon has come to an end with over 900 hackers participating and over 200 projects made over a single weekend. It is the biggest hackathon ever in LatAm.</p><p>The main goal of these events is to connect Ethereans together and strenghen the community around creating cool stuff. I'd like to share my experience so that buidlers who are on the fence about participating in these events can get a sense of how cool it is to get together and buidl with buidlers in the same buidling.</p><p>Once you decide to go to a Hackathon you should start brainstorming about what you would like to buidl. It can literally be anything but I personally like to think about a specific problem i'd like to solve. At first it may feel like a pretty daunting task. But the most important thing about these events is that you're not alone. If you cant come up with anything its time to talk to other people and see what theyre trying to build and join the team that you find the most interesting. Although you can hack solo, you have way better chances if you join up with others that can complent your skillset and bring new ideas into the project. </p><p>EthGlobal.com runs the hackathon events like a well oiled machine. You have plenty of avenues to reach out and connect to other people and there are several mentors available alongisde with the teams that sponsor the event in order to get more people to use their stack. I met my team members through the discord chat and after a team building event early on. At the event itself you have infinite coffee and plenty of food to keep you going throughout the weekend. ALthough the internet does get shoddy at times with all the npm installs going on.</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="let-the-hack-begin">Let the Hack Begin!<a class="hash-link" href="#let-the-hack-begin" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h4><p>Once your team has been formed and the hackathon officially begins. Its off to the races. Every team has a different strategy, but there are some important things to consider. The goal of the event is to showcase an idea, not necesarily a production stage. You want to get to the proof of concept as soon as possible and then build extra functionalities on top. You can stay at the venue 24/7 and a big percentage of people do, but it is also important to pace youself so that you can do good presentations at the end. </p><p>An important thing to keep in mind is that you dont necesarly need to be a super coder to participate in these events. There is a lot of work to be done in any project around documentation, graphic design, product ideation and narrative that really makes a difference to make your project stand out. </p><p>The judging process for the hacks is very brief and you dont really get too much time to go over small details, so its important to get straight to the point and try to have a long lasting impression. At the end of the day the Hackathon is not about winning but rather sharing ideas and connecting to people. I hope more Nerds will start participating in these events soon. Here is our submission to the hackathon. If you find it interesting and would like to help out with this idea feel free to reach out at the NerdQuarters.</p><center># [Allyu.xyz ](https://Allyu.xyz ) ![](https://i.imgur.com/cikwHhm.png)<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="a-community-based-protocol-to-issue-crypto-backed-money">A community-based protocol to issue crypto-backed money<a class="hash-link" href="#a-community-based-protocol-to-issue-crypto-backed-money" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2></center><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="objectives">Objectives:<a class="hash-link" href="#objectives" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li>To create a system that communities can leverage to issue their own trustless paper money backed entirely by crypto deposits.</li><li>Onboard community leaders into crypto and enable them to lead by example in the adoption of web3.</li><li>To increase the transactability of Ethereum based products by introducing them into the heart of the Latin American community: the corner store. allowing recipients to purchase food and other vital supplies with crypto money</li></ul><p>.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="introduction">Introduction<a class="hash-link" href="#introduction" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>In order to gain mass adoption, Web3 protocols need to start with the simplest use cases in order to address the needs of a majority of the world's population. The singular most impactful use case for blockchains is to serve as money. Money has three main characteristics: it serves as a store of value, as a medium of exchange, and as a unit of account. These three characteristics are not independent of each other since once any kind of money has value it can be used to fulfill those three functions. However, we can argue that there are some forms of money that are better than others at one of these aspects while lacking in others.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="crypto-vs-fiat-as-a-medium-of-echange">Crypto vs Fiat as a Medium of Echange<a class="hash-link" href="#crypto-vs-fiat-as-a-medium-of-echange" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p align="center"></p><table><thead><tr><th>Pros</th><th>Cons</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Verifiable</td><td>Costlier</td></tr><tr><td>Uncensorable</td><td>Slower</td></tr><tr><td>Fungible</td><td>Requires Onboarding</td></tr></tbody></table><p></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="ranking-of-the-online-banking-penetration-in-latin-america-and-the-caribbean-by-country-2020">Ranking of the online banking penetration in Latin America and the Caribbean by Country 2020<a class="hash-link" href="#ranking-of-the-online-banking-penetration-in-latin-america-and-the-caribbean-by-country-2020" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/lIYjU3m.png" class="img_ev3q"></p><h1>Smartphone penetration in Latin America</h1><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/xTsQA8c.png" class="img_ev3q"></p><center><h1>How to leapfrog LatAm over Online Banking into Web3?</h1><h1>Do what Online Banking couldn't:</h1><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="replace-fiat-paper">Replace fiat paper.<a class="hash-link" href="#replace-fiat-paper" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="with-crypto-paper">With Crypto Paper<a class="hash-link" href="#with-crypto-paper" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/VauTrNE.jpg" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/eUGQ9bM.png" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/YS4jQBB.png" class="img_ev3q"></p></center><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="pitfalls-todo--future-work">Pitfalls ToDO &amp; future work<a class="hash-link" href="#pitfalls-todo--future-work" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>1) Protect claims from frontrunning when supplying private &amp; public key</p><div class="codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-text codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">- Future hash commit the withdraw transaction (a la ENS)</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">- ZK proof of ownership of secret pair for withrdrawal</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg class="copyButtonIcon_y97N" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div><p>2) Decentralize further by giving trusted community leaders the ability to issue new papers themselves</p><div class="codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-text codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">- PolygonId based reputation enables issuing allowance</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">- MPC to create a split secret that allows printing bills on regular printer at home</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg class="copyButtonIcon_y97N" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-to-scale-decentralize-the-printer">How to scale: Decentralize the printer<a class="hash-link" href="#how-to-scale-decentralize-the-printer" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h4><p>→ Corner stores are at the heart of Latin American communities</p><p>→ Store owners already provide several financial services: Cash in checks, pay for utilities, mobile phone plans</p><p>→ A reputation system can be implemented to represent existing trust on-chain</p><p>→ Trusted store owners can print papers as a service for customers who then add their balance</p><center>![](https://i.imgur.com/jUQAHSy.png)</center><p>Github: <a href="https://github.com/allyu-xyz" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/allyu-xyz</a>
Join the Nerds: <a href="https://y.at/%F0%9F%A4%93%E2%9C%89%EF%B8%8F%F0%9F%A4%93" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://y.at/%F0%9F%A4%93%E2%9C%89%EF%B8%8F%F0%9F%A4%93</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>nerddao</category>
            <category>hacks</category>
            <category>ethereum</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nerd DAO Delegation proposal]]></title>
            <link>https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/nerddao/blog/NerdOS</link>
            <guid>/NerdOS</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 02:08:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Introduction]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="introduction">Introduction<a class="hash-link" href="#introduction" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>What is Nerd DAO?</p><p>Nerd DAO is a post-work collective of highly capable individuals who gather to talk about anything related to being a Nerd. we tend to talk about cryptocurrencies and the latest developments in science art technology politics and economics. everyone is welcome and its free to join as long as you stay nerdy.</p><p> A word about myself. I'm known online as At0x.eth. Before being in crypto I became a M.D but took interest in data science and worked with a research group publishing several papers. Basically, I have always been a huge nerd. I used to play countless hours of WoW as a kid and have been running VR side hustles for over 5 years now. </p><center><iframe src="https://giphy.com/embed/xghFgmOKbk0G4" width="480" height="321" frameborder="0" class="giphy-embed" allowfullscreen=""></iframe><p><a href="https://giphy.com/gifs/smiling-spongebob-squarepants-nerd-xghFgmOKbk0G4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">via GIPHY</a></p></center><p>I've been aware of blockchain for a long time but did only start participating around june 2020 because covid made me reconsider my carreer choice. When I first joined into crypto telegram madness, I found there was no room for deep technical discourse if it was not related to a "when pump" statement. In a space where "in it for the technology" is used as a joke I needed to create a group where we're really in it for the tech. a place for Nerds.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="enter-the-nerdquarters">Enter The NerdQuarters<a class="hash-link" href="#enter-the-nerdquarters" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p><a href="https://y.at/%F0%9F%A4%93%E2%9C%89%EF%B8%8F%F0%9F%A4%93" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://y.at/🤓✉️🤓</a></p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/MantluU.jpg" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>The Nerdquarters is the core of the Nerd community. We have created an open source community where nerds come and share information to make sense of it together. It is also a place for newcomers to ask questions and avoid repeating the same mistakes we've already learned from.</p><p>As we have grown we have started to interact with alot of new tools for decentralized communities which have allowed us to coordinate to embark on several ventures. We dont need venture capital money because we do everything in house. We just want to have fun and experience the growth of the infinite machine. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="nerd-dao">NERD DAO<a class="hash-link" href="#nerd-dao" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The Nerd DAO is the on chain representation of the NERD commuinity. We created the DAO using <a href="https://ethos.eth.link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">EthOS</a>.  EthOS is a permissionless and decentralized governance protocol that allows anyone to create their own DAO with its own token, treasury and governance interface. We are one of the earliest external users of EthOS. </p><p>The Nerd DAO is not explicitly intended to be a for profit venture. The initial tokens were airdropped to members of the telegram chat. Over 80% of the supply is still held by the Treasury wallet. There are no insider backers and nobody has special privileges or access over the token. Furthermore the NERD Treasury owns the initial LP used for the token. However, we have undertaken for profit ventures in the form of products and services such as our Nerd Fungible Trust group investment and our upcoming <!-- -->[Redacted]<!-- --> trading platform which will pay fees to the DAO.</p><p>Through all these ventures and experiences we have learned a thing or two about how the metaverse is being built. We have also started to etch our own corned of the metaverse by starting to interconnect experiences and information through Web3 interfaces. As our network becomes more expansive we're starting to learn what the metaverse really is and how its different from the way we used to do things. As proof, here's a picture of our latest development meeting for one of our projects.</p><center><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/EzihW4B.png" class="img_ev3q"></p></center><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="nerd-dao--metaverse-manifesto">Nerd DAO  Metaverse Manifesto<a class="hash-link" href="#nerd-dao--metaverse-manifesto" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ul><li><p>We believe that the Metaverse is a series of interconected experiences through which an individual can traverse while preserving their identity. </p><ul><li>In that context we believe that the role of the Nerd DAO is to create and connect experiences for its members to traverse. We are here to buidl our corner of the Metaverse.</li></ul></li><li><p>We believe that a metaverse is a place for human connection and therefore our goal is to make it enticing for people to inhabit our spaces in order to collaborate, play and learn together.</p></li><li><p>We know that the metaverse HAS to be fun. If the metaverse feels like work, you're not doing it right.</p></li></ul><p>Nerd has no papers of incorporation, no headquarters, nor even a list of names and locations for its contributors</p><p>We follow <a href="https://twitter.com/iearnfinance/status/1445799269189881864?s=20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Yearn's</a> radical decentralization model. Which means that anyone can join up our community and contribute. Join the Nerdquarters chat! We are always talking about the daily happenings and there's plenty of people eager to explain away any questions others may have. Once you are there you can join our development groups or create your own and recieve help and guidance from the other nerds on how to apply your time to start your crypto adventure.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="nerds-3-ethos">Nerds &lt;3 EthOS<a class="hash-link" href="#nerds-3-ethos" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The purpose of the NERD delegation for ETHOs will be to create venues and opportunities to showcase the power of the ETHOS protocol as a tool to build an online community. By creating forkable products that solve different challenges nerds face (such as trustless bitcoin bridges or AI NFTs) we can increase useage of the EthOS protocol by enhancing the smart contract  landscape of the base layer <!-- -->[what a sentence!!]</p><p>Adittionaly NerdDAO will spearhead the organization of a recurrent hackathon and digital event to showcase and support projects built with the EthOS stack. We will demonstrate how different problems can be solved using the codebase and have a dev team trained to create front ends for contracts deployed using EthOS factories.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="scope-of-the-nerd-delegation">Scope of the NERD Delegation<a class="hash-link" href="#scope-of-the-nerd-delegation" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The purpose of the NERD delegation is to showcase EthereansOS protocol asa a tool to build decentralized communities. this includes several avenues:</p><p>1) Utilizing and showcasing the use of EthOS protocol on products developed by Nerd
2) Creating a starter kit to simplify developing interfaces with EthOS products
3) Organizing events to communicate the goals of the protocol, create products that leverage the EthOS stack and showcase products and communities built on it</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Building a Crypto Perpetual Motion Machine]]></title>
            <link>https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/nerddao/blog/perpetual-motion</link>
            <guid>perpetual-motion</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 02:08:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA["Oh ye seekers after perpetual motion, how many vain chimeras have you pursued? Go and take your place with the alchemists."]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/0PBLeYw.jpg" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><strong><em>"Oh ye seekers after perpetual motion, how many vain chimeras have you pursued? Go and take your place with the alchemists."</em></strong> </p><p>— Leonardo da Vinci, 1494</p><p>Perpetual motion is the motion of bodies that <strong><em>continues forever in an unperturbed system. A perpetual motion machine is a hypothetical machine that can do work infinitely without an external energy source.</em></strong> This kind of machine is impossible, as it would violate either the first or second law of thermodynamics or both.</p><p>Luckily for us we're dealing with the laws of crypto economics, not thermodynamics. The behavior of monetary systems can in fact be modeled using Physic's first principles and the inmaterial nature of it allows for the creation of systems that go beyon the constraints of the phisical world. However, the laws of thermodiamics offer a glimpse of what is required to create an infinitely sustainable monetary system, which in fact is a perpetual motion machine.</p><p><strong><em>The first law</em></strong> describes the of conservation of energy states postulating that the total energy of any isolated system (for which energy and matter transfer through the system boundary are not possible) is constant; energy can be transformed from one form to another, but can be neither created nor destroyed.</p><p><strong><em>The second law</em></strong> may be formulated by the observation that the entropy of isolated systems left to spontaneous evolution cannot decrease, as they always arrive at a state of thermodynamic equilibrium where the entropy is highest at the given internal energy</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="money-is-a-form-of-energy">Money is a form of Energy<a class="hash-link" href="#money-is-a-form-of-energy" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>In physics, <strong><em>energy</em></strong> is the quantitative property that is transferred to a body or to a physical system, recognizable in the performance of work. Energy is a conserved quantity; the law of conservation of energy states that energy can be converted in form, but not created or destroyed. Money is any item or verifiable record that is generally accepted as payment for goods and services and repayment of debts, such as taxes. In other words, both money and energy can be described as a quantitative property that is transfered in exchange for work. Unlike energy however, money can in fact be created and destroyed. Which is the first key we need to create a perpetual motion machine</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="can-entropy-be-reduced">Can Entropy be Reduced?<a class="hash-link" href="#can-entropy-be-reduced" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p><strong><em>“THERE IS AS YET INSUFFICIENT DATA FOR A MEANINGFUL ANSWER.”</em></strong></p><p>-Multivac, 2061</p><p><strong><em>Entropy</em></strong> is a scientific concept as well as a measurable physical property that is most commonly associated with a state of disorder, randomness, or uncertainty. In the phisical world the overall entropy always increases: things tend to go from a state of order to disorder if left unchecked. Although the total entropy of the universe cannot ever decrease energy (read: money) can be spent to fight off entropy locally. Thats why we eat food in order and reduce our body entropy by repairing and replacing cells. Ultimately however, in the physical world entropy always wins. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="entropy-reduction--value-creation">Entropy Reduction = Value Creation<a class="hash-link" href="#entropy-reduction--value-creation" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Imagine you could deploy custom laws of physics. Thats what solidity is like. If entropy is a measure of unceartanty smart contracts are anti-entropy devices for they describe deterministic functions that organize energy(read: money). For example; The UniSwap smart contracts organize thousands of pairs from houndreds of thousands of users in order to allow atomic swaps between any asset pair. The fact that UniSwap is deployed in the network reduces the total entropy and increased the value of everything within.</p><p>In the case of StrudelDAO our source of entropy is the vBTC peg. Our protocol aims to reduce this entropy by deploying incentive structures that produce energy (read: money) in order to incentivize actions that achieve this goal. Once we manage to achieve the peg we know that value will have ben created for the protocol which we can compound on by offering a product that can be built upon by other protocols which are also creating on chain value. </p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/X0iDfFy.png" class="img_ev3q">
<img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/ycdmrfp.png" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-strudel-bitcoin-metabolism">the Strudel Bitcoin Metabolism<a class="hash-link" href="#the-strudel-bitcoin-metabolism" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/yoDN0iB.png" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>The above graphic is a schematic of an enzimatic pathway. In Biological systems enzimatic pathways are a series of chemical reactions that transform a molecule for a specific purpose. Aditionally, enzimes are interoperable and often have multiple uses throughout the body. Furthermore, enzimatic processes often trigger multiple other processes downstream to create complex behaviours found throughout nature.</p><p>The Strudel Protocol employs a similar approach to the design of the incentive scheme for the vBTC peg. In order to produce a pegged Bitcoin asset the protocol employs multiple incentive mechanisms in multiple chains to create complex arbitrage patterns that peg vBTC to the Bitcoin price. </p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/9z9ZRlc.png" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="entering-the-strudel">Entering the Strudel<a class="hash-link" href="#entering-the-strudel" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>The strudel protocol creates an incentive for users to bridge BTC into the ethereum network due to an arbitrage between the vBTC price and BTC price. The price of vBTC is determined by the existing liquidity. Whenever vBTC is above the peg new coins are minted to close the arbitrage. Once inside the ETH network users can use their vBTC in a variety of yield farming oppportunities to earn $TRDL tokens. </p><p>The current deployed components of the protocol interacting with vBTC are:</p><ul><li>ETH<ul><li>Strudel Protocol<ul><li>Bridge Contracts</li><li>MasterChef yield farm</li></ul></li></ul></li><li>Bridge<ul><li>Multichain.xyz<ul><li>ETH&lt;-&gt;FTM bridge</li></ul></li></ul></li><li>FTM<ul><li>ORKAN<ul><li>Bonds<ul><li>vBTC</li><li>$M</li></ul></li></ul></li><li>MitiCushqui<ul><li>Stablecoin<ul><li>$M</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="orkanization">Orkanization<a class="hash-link" href="#orkanization" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>In the FTM network, ORKAN offers perpetual bonds offering Orkan tokens for vBTC and $M which generate consistent buying pressure for vBTC which pulls tokens from the Ethereum network into Fantom. Orkan aims to create the largest on chain BTC repository and removes vBTC from circulation, reducing the floating circulating supply and increasing the mainnet vBTC price. At the same time, the reserves acquired will be deployed in order to obtain interest bearing opportunities for $M and vBTC holders throughout the FTM DeFi ecosystem</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="back-to-basics-btc-backed-reserve-currency">Back to Basics: BTC Backed Reserve Currency<a class="hash-link" href="#back-to-basics-btc-backed-reserve-currency" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>The last piece of the puzzle is our stablecoin issuing procotol: <a href="https://y.at/%F0%9F%8F%A6%F0%9F%92%B0%F0%9F%92%B5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">mitiCushqui🏦💰💵</a>. This protocol issues a stablecoin backed by USDC and vBTC. We created an oracle that pegs vBTC to the BTC price effectively creating an arbitrage that will mint $M at a discount and redeem for $USDC as long as vBTC is under the peg.  Once the arbitrage is closed $M issuance will serve as a backstop to preserve the vBTC peg as the BTC price varies. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="perpetual-motion">Perpetual Motion<a class="hash-link" href="#perpetual-motion" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>The incentive structures decribed above should generate perpetual motion by creating a system which tends to return equilibrium point where vBTC is pegged to the BTC price.  If such state of homeostasis is achieved the system would go on forever mantaining a stable peg for a growing vBTC market. The implications of this scenario for the Strudel Protocol are inmense: </p><ul><li>Strudel could secure a significant portion of the BTC network for the DeFi ecosystem forever. Merging BTC and DeFI irreversively.  </li><li>ORKAN would become the biggest on chain decentralized repository of BTC. </li><li>$M would become one of the most reliable reserve currencies in DeFi, serving as a base asset for many other community specific stable assets.</li></ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>strudel</category>
            <category>bitcoin</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is 🧠🧠🧠🤓?]]></title>
            <link>https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/nerddao/blog/what-is-nerd</link>
            <guid>what-is-nerd</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 02:08:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Introduction]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="introduction">Introduction<a class="hash-link" href="#introduction" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>What is NerdDAO🧠🧠🧠🤓?</p><p>In principle, it's a newsletter that's going to try and record NerdDAO Activity. Instead of "publishing" a periodical this is going to be a long form series of articles which can be accessed through <a href="https://y.at/%F0%9F%A7%A0%F0%9F%A7%A0%F0%9F%A7%A0%F0%9F%A4%93" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://y.at/🧠🧠🧠🤓</a>. I'm going to try and get notable members of the Nerdquarters to contribute on a varied range of subjects. </p><p> A word about myself. I'm known online as At0x.eth. Before being in crypto I became a M.D but took interest in data science and worked with a research group publishing several papers. Basically, I have always been a huge nerd. I used to play countless hours of WoW as a kid and have been running VR side hustles for over 5 years now. </p><center><iframe src="https://giphy.com/embed/xghFgmOKbk0G4" width="480" height="321" frameborder="0" class="giphy-embed" allowfullscreen=""></iframe><p><a href="https://giphy.com/gifs/smiling-spongebob-squarepants-nerd-xghFgmOKbk0G4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">via GIPHY</a></p></center><p>I've been aware of blockchain for a long time but did only start participating around june 2020 because covid made me reconsider my carreer choice. When I first joined into crypto telegram madness, I found there was no room for deep technical discourse if it was not related to a "when pump" statement. In a space where "in it for the technology" is used as a joke I needed to create a group where we're really in it for the tech. a place for Nerds.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="enter-the-nerdquarters">Enter The NerdQuarters<a class="hash-link" href="#enter-the-nerdquarters" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p><a href="https://y.at/%F0%9F%A4%93%E2%9C%89%EF%B8%8F%F0%9F%A4%93" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://y.at/🤓✉️🤓</a></p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/MantluU.jpg" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>The Nerdquarters is the core of the Nerd community. We have created an open source community where nerds come and share information to make sense of it together. It is also a place for newcomers to ask questions and avoid repeating the same mistakes we've already learned from.</p><p>As we have grown we have started to interact with alot of new tools for decentralized communities which have allowed us to coordinate to embark on several ventures. We dont need venture capital money because we do everything in house. We just want to have fun and experience the growth of the infinite machine. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="nerd-dao">NERD DAO<a class="hash-link" href="#nerd-dao" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The Nerd DAO is the on chain representation of the NERD commuinity. We created the DAO using <a href="https://ethos.eth.link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">EthOS</a>.  EthOS is a permissionless and decentralized governance protocol that allows anyone to create their own DAO with its own token, treasury and governance interface. We are one of the earliest external users of EthOS. </p><p>The Nerd DAO is not explicitly intended to be a for profit venture. The initial tokens were airdropped to members of the telegram chat. Over 80% of the supply is still held by the Treasury wallet. There are no insider backers and nobody has special privileges or access over the token. Furthermore the NERD Treasury owns the initial LP used for the token. However, we have undertaken for profit ventures in the form of products and services such as our Nerd Fungible Trust group investment and our upcoming <!-- -->[Redacted]<!-- --> trading platform which will pay fees to the DAO.</p><p>Through all these ventures and experiences we have learned a thing or two about how the metaverse is being built. We have also started to etch our own corned of the metaverse by starting to interconnect experiences and information through Web3 interfaces. As our network becomes more expansive we're starting to learn what the metaverse really is and how its different from the way we used to do things. As proof, here's a picture of our latest development meeting for one of our projects.</p><center><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/EzihW4B.png" class="img_ev3q"></p></center><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="nerd-dao--metaverse-manifesto">Nerd DAO  Metaverse Manifesto<a class="hash-link" href="#nerd-dao--metaverse-manifesto" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ul><li><p><strong><em>We believe that the Metaverse is a series of interconected experiences through which an individual can traverse while preserving their identity. </em></strong></p><ul><li>In that context we believe that the role of the Nerd DAO is to create and connect experiences for its members to traverse. We are here to buidl our corner of the Metaverse.</li></ul></li><li><p><strong><em>We believe that a metaverse is a place for human connection and therefore our goal is to make it enticing for people to inhabit our spaces in order to collaborate, play and learn together.</em></strong></p></li><li><p><strong><em>We know that the metaverse HAS to be fun. If the metaverse feels like work, we're not there yet.</em></strong></p></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-to-participate">How To Participate?<a class="hash-link" href="#how-to-participate" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Q: Who can contribute to Nerd?</p><p>A: You</p><p>Nerd has no papers of incorporation, no headquarters, nor even a list of names and locations for its contributors</p><p>We follow <a href="https://twitter.com/iearnfinance/status/1445799269189881864?s=20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Yearn's</a> radical decentralization model. Which means that anyone can join up our community and contribute. Join the Nerdquarters chat! We are always talking about the daily happenings and there's plenty of people eager to explain away any questions others may have. Once you are there you can join our development groups or create your own and recieve help and guidance from the other nerds on how to apply your time to start your crypto adventure.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="explore-our-metaverse--httpsyatf09f92bbf09fa493f09f92b0">Explore our Metaverse:  <a href="https://y.at/%F0%9F%92%BB%F0%9F%A4%93%F0%9F%92%B0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://y.at/%F0%9F%92%BB%F0%9F%A4%93%F0%9F%92%B0</a><a class="hash-link" href="#explore-our-metaverse--httpsyatf09f92bbf09fa493f09f92b0" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>nerddao</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Strudel Bitcoin Investment Briefing]]></title>
            <link>https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/nerddao/blog/strudel-briefing</link>
            <guid>strudel-briefing</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The Strudel Bridge]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-strudel-bridge">The Strudel Bridge<a class="hash-link" href="#the-strudel-bridge" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/xKZ9G1Z.png" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><strong>By eliminating the need for custodial control of assets</strong> that come with typical wrappers, the Strudel protocol trades off counter-party risk for market risk while using <strong>market dynamics, crypto-economic incentives, and cross-chain capabilities</strong> to maintain a pegged, scalable, and capital-efficient ecosystem. This one-of-a-kind economic approach offers average users and big money investors numerous options for monetary growth and grants more diversity and security to DeFi.</p><h1>Problem Statement</h1><p><strong>Bitcoin</strong>  is poorly incorporated into web3. The existing landscape relies mainly on wBTC, a trusted bridge operated primarily by funds such as 3AC, which have the exclusive right to mint and burn wBTC, therefore cornering the benefit of the arbitrage between on-chain BTC and legacy markets.</p><p>Vitalik <a href="https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/1295252403558559746?s=20&amp;t=UvAU_6bfaNeaIVcafixefg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">has stated</a> that trusted BTC bridges pose a systemic risk to the DeFi ecosystem. I would go even further and say that DeFi cannot grow until its intimately integrated with BTC and we capture a significant % of the BTC network on-chain. To achieve this goal, we must find a robust solution to bridge many BTC into the Web3 economy.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-on-chain-bitcoin-landscape">The On Chain Bitcoin Landscape<a class="hash-link" href="#the-on-chain-bitcoin-landscape" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p><a href="https://dune.com/eliasimos/btc-on-ethereum_1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Updated Dashboard</a>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/AyKNaM9.png" class="img_ev3q">
<img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/vYAyc5x.png" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><strong>Key Takeaways</strong></p><ul><li>Less than 1.5% of the BTC supply is currently bridged on-chain.</li><li>On-chain, BTC balances are very stable compared to price volatility.</li><li>Trusted bridges (wBTC+hBTC) represent over 90% of all the BTC bridged on-chain.</li><li>Decentralized alternatives have not found strong PmF: RenBTC only has 4,000 BTC bridged. Hardly 2% of the total on-chain BTC</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="strudel-bridge-architecture">Strudel Bridge Architecture<a class="hash-link" href="#strudel-bridge-architecture" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>When BTC is requested to be transferred using the Strudel dApp, a transaction output with the transfer amount and the receiving Ethereum wallet address is created. This output is handed to the user’s Bitcoin wallet through the QR code. When a user signs a transfer, the resulting transaction might look like this.</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/eGRRlhh.png" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Next, the header of the Bitcoin block containing the transaction needs to be registered in the relayer contract on Ethereum, where its proof-of-work is verified, and the canonical chain is extended. Simple payment verification (SPV), a protocol used by Bitcoin light clients and wallets, prevents invalid blocks from entering the relayer.
Once the transaction containing the burn has been buried under enough proof of work (6 blocks), an inclusion proof is relayed onto Ethereum. The proof is verified by the Strudel contract, which mints vBTC in a ratio of 1:1 to the designated Ethereum address. The protocol strictly mints one vBTC for one burned BTC, not taking any fees for bridge crossings.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="strudel-bitcoin">Strudel Bitcoin<a class="hash-link" href="#strudel-bitcoin" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Token Address: 0xe1406825186d63980fd6e2ec61888f7b91c4bae4</p><p>Current vBTC Supply: 23.27238764 </p><p>Token Distribution:</p><p>Hodlers: 461 </p><p>Total Liquidity: ~120,000 USD combined</p><p>Market Cap: 230,000 USD</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/llQkTCg.png" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Once BTC crosses the bridge using the Strudel Protocol its issued as Strudel Bitcoin (vBTC) on the Ethereum network. vBTC is <strong>fully erc20 compliant</strong> with 18 decimals and flash loan capabilities. </p><p><a href="https://etherscan.io/token/0xe1406825186d63980fd6e2ec61888f7b91c4bae4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://etherscan.io/token/0xe1406825186d63980fd6e2ec61888f7b91c4bae4</a>
<a href="https://ftmscan.com/token/0x9049198f6b21acf1e050cfcf36a6879a07b0bbe4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://ftmscan.com/token/0x9049198f6b21acf1e050cfcf36a6879a07b0bbe4</a></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="historic-performance">Historic Performance<a class="hash-link" href="#historic-performance" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/vVcjWIe.png" class="img_ev3q">
<img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/c5Jhu6c.png" class="img_ev3q"></p><ul><li>vBTC has outperformed both ETH (+86%) and BTC (+53%) YTD</li><li>The Strudel Protocol controls &gt; 50% of vBTC, which are acquired through Orkan.Finance bond issuance and MitiCushqui stablecoin issuance.</li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="liquidity-landscape">Liquidity landscape<a class="hash-link" href="#liquidity-landscape" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>Strudel utilizes a <a href="https://app.gitbook.com/o/V40TVngLYntzpq24zWhI/s/9QESb5e46FBDH1t8kShd/monetary-policy/mandates" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">mandate based approach</a> to guide the development of the protocol</p><p><strong>Mandate #1 - Achieve true decentralization of BTC on DeFi
Mandate #2  - Design incentive structures that issue and manage reserve backed currencies</strong></p><p>By utilizing vBTC as a reserve asset, we reduce the floating supply and therefore provide price stability when interacting with demand driven by incentives to provide liquidity for vBTC</p><p><strong>Liquidity Incentives</strong></p><p>The first stop for vBTC once bridged is the strudel. Finance farms. The protocol utilizes a sushi-style LP farm to issue 1 $TRDL per block split evenly among the following positions:</p><ul><li>$TRDL:ETH(Pool0) (320%APY)</li><li>vBTC:$TRDL (73.51%APY)</li><li>vBTC:ETH (14.96%APY)</li><li>vNFT::vBTC:PUNK:CC:BAYC (NA* APY)</li></ul><p>*have to develop code to calculate price on multi asset pool to use in APY formula. </p><p><strong>Reserve Backed Currencies</strong></p><p><strong>Orkan.finance</strong></p><p><strong>$vBTC's peg through The Orkan</strong> </p><ul><li>When $vBTC gets under the peg, $ORK bonds are issued to increase the treasury supply and therefore remove $vBTC from circulation</li><li>When $vBTC gets above the peg, previously acquired $vBTC is exchanged by the protocol for other assets to diversify the treasury basket or to buy back and burn $ORK.</li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/b2V7Yoo.png" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><strong>vBTC as a Store of Value</strong></p><p>The Orkan treasury has managed to retain most of the value issued for the purchase of vBTC even though the market has gone through a significant downturn. ORK is trading at .40c, whereas the backing per token is 1.22c.</p><p><strong>🏦💰💵MitiCushqui🏦💰💵</strong></p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/axrQqVG.png" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>We recently deployed MitiCushqui, a <a href="https://y.at/%F0%9F%8F%A6%F0%9F%92%B0%F0%9F%92%B5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">stablecoin issuing protocol</a>. This protocol can be used to deploy redeemable stablecoins backed by a fixed ratio of a base stablecoin and any other asset. </p><p>The protocol oracles the BTC price and therefore creates an arbitrage where users can mint $Miti  at a discount and redeem for USDC. The vault keeps vBTC out of circulation therefore reducing the supply and increasing the price until the arbitrage is closed and the peg is met. </p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/UC5UXFw.png" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-future-of-bitcoin-is-on-chain-and-the-on-chain-future-is-bitcoin">The Future of Bitcoin is on-chain and the on-chain future is Bitcoin.<a class="hash-link" href="#the-future-of-bitcoin-is-on-chain-and-the-on-chain-future-is-bitcoin" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>To make the web3 ecosystem more robust, we need to onboard a more significant percentage of BTC on-chain. A way to achieve reliable yields is to incentivize the flow of BTC into Web3. This capital can finance projects that generate value for the entire space. This makes BTC more useful, which is vital For it to gain mainstream adoption.</p><p>The future of BTC cannot depend on any one group of developers or caretakers. To realize its potential, we must find ways to bridge it into the Web3 ecosystem by utilizing as many techniques as possible and later building tools to create an interoperable interface</p><p>Learn More:</p><p>Strudel Twitter: @EnterTheStrudel
At0x Twitter: @At0xNQ
Nerd Chat: <a href="https://y.at/%F0%9F%A4%93%E2%9C%89%EF%B8%8F%F0%9F%A4%93" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://y.at/🤓✉️🤓</a>
Strudel Landing: <a href="https://y.at/%F0%9F%8C%AA%F0%9F%8C%AA%F0%9F%91%80" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://y.at/🌪🌪👀</a>
MitiCushqui: <a href="https://y.at/%F0%9F%8F%A6%F0%9F%92%B0%F0%9F%92%B5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://y.at/🏦💰💵</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>strudel</category>
            <category>bitcoin</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>